[Music]
hello everyone this week i wanted to
share some of the progress i've been
making in my new home
i've been ever so slowly trying to find
time outside of work to put things in
place and organize
i'm still a long ways away from getting
things to where i'd like them to be
however i have started my flower garden
made plans for future tidying of the
property and of course adopted more
house plants because apparently
three dozen isn't enough
i am currently working on painting the
walls and so far it is taking forever
but i hope to show you what i've been up
to very soon
[Music]
at the end of this video i'm going to go
more into detail on how i transform my
space using simple techniques and focus
on second-hand repurposed and gifted
items for a very unique look
however i will say that changing your
space doesn't necessarily mean bringing
new items into your home
instead before i make any decisions i
like to focus on my senses usually that
means sitting experiencing the space
considering how i want to feel when i
enter my home
be that vibrant energetic or peaceful
and tranquil a consideration for me is
what my pets enjoy as well for example
my cat and bunny like sunlight and quiet
eiker loves classical music and rugs
for the sense of sight i like to hang
fascinators in my windows and all types
of fun little items made of glass that
capture the sun rays and cast rainbows
on the floor as well as curtains that
filter the light
i also think how a space smells has a
conscious and subconscious effect on how
we feel so i consider candles and
diffusers to be important
[Music]
in order to transform a normal piece of
furniture and make it more unique i like
to change the knobs as well as add
little decorative accents
for example this dining table is quite
worn and i will be sanding it and
painting it very soon
stay tuned in the next week or two for a
more or less completed house tour so you
can see how the space is starting to
come together and hopefully feel
inspired to imbue your personality into
where you live and really set free your
creativity
[Music]
so
of course my house wouldn't feel
complete if it wasn't for my pets and
cozy evenings after work baking with
them
[Music]
do
while my home is still not
absolutely 100 complete i did want to
share at least what i have done
and i also am going to share a completed
home tour
hopefully next week
complete complete home tour because
we are finally finally mostly complete
with renovations so
you also probably know from my past
videos i am very passionate about
budgeting and finances and simple living
and frugality where possible and also
taking into consideration
sustainability so for me
my answer my simple answer to bringing
nature into consideration in regards to
my space is to buy things secondhand
where possible
for example this shirt it's a
[Music]
because i am an etsy shop owner i of
course love to support other etsy shops
that is something that's very important
to me in order to help other businesses
across the world i also try to purchase
some items locally that i normally
wouldn't get second hand for example i
have a very hard time finding rugs
secondhand that are not
smelly a lot of rugs that are very old
just have a smell that i can't get out
of it no matter how many times they
shampoo it
so that is one thing i decided to get
new but a lot of things even luke had a
lot of furniture in his home some of it
which i have sanded and repurposed and
painted i also wanted to have a very
lovely
hi baby
eiger is here
i don't think that there's any reason
that anyone needs to go out and buy
expensive items to transform their space
and i think it comes down to for me at
least some very basic principles that
make a huge difference
and those are in regards to your senses
and for me whenever i am thinking about
how i want to make a space more
conducive to
helping my anxiety helping me feel like
my best self i think that so many videos
i see focus so much on the visual appeal
i love making videos that are
all about visual beauty and nature and
a home life
but
i think that is perhaps the least
important part in a way because i think
how your space feels encompasses so much
more than its aesthetic quality so one
thing that i do always think about is
sounds i like to
hang up
items such as
soft wind chimes or have a little
fountain running in my house that just
sounds calming and brings me back to
nature one of my favorite things is
having a little water fountain
music or ambient sounds into your space
when you're there on a very very low
level can really make a big difference i
know some people just prefer complete
silence in their homes but if you are
someone that likes interesting nature
sounds you could take that into
consideration
and that can be involved into your home
on a very low budget you know a small
fountain where wind chime
you know is pretty easy to do i also
like hanging a bird feeder
near my house so that i get a lot of
birds coming nearby and all their sounds
are always very appealing to me how your
space smells is also very important for
me especially because i have a lot of
pets so it can smell like dog hair
very quickly i love to use smokeless
incense or oil or my preferred wishes
usually a candle in order to make the
space smell really fresh and nice and of
course that goes hand in hand with
sweeping and vacuuming but it is
something that really makes a big
difference and smells
do make a difference with how we feel
what we smell really does impact us more
than we think i also like
hanging little glass fascinators on my
window if i get direct light so that it
can cast little rainbows on the ground
it makes such a wonderful difference
even if you have a space that's simple
it just having that light come in in
such an interesting way i always find
really makes me happy i also really love
to use little um
decorative edges i don't know what
they're called but i'll show some images
of them but i love to use those little
decorative edges in order to
add something really interesting
to a window or a corner in my kitchen it
always makes such a difference it's very
specific to my style which is a little
more old-fashioned and whimsical but i
thought i would offer that as an option
to you as well i love hanging things in
my windows that are always interesting i
love having plants having life in my
space even if you don't get direct light
you can use plant lights
and just bring in so much life and
loveliness in your space i hope this was
somewhat interesting to you it's
definitely a passion project for me i
just
love decorating and now what i'm gonna
go ahead and do is try painting the
walls a little bit with some fun designs
and show you how
strange
lady i am
that i want to paint birds on my wall so
um yes
maybe if you are a little fairy at heart
you may also want to imbue your space
with some of this
pixie dust but if not listen to your
heart whatever works for you and
whatever makes you feel comfortable it's
not about things it's about the feeling
you're looking for in your space
i'm sending my love wishing you a
wonderful week goodbye
[Music]
you